Joonwon Choi

Formal Verification Engineer at Apple One Apple Park Way, Cupertino, CA 95014 +1-339-225-5940 | joonwonc@apple.com | http://joonwon.net/c

Current Position

Formal Verification Engineer, Apple

03/15/2021 -Current

I have worked on formally verifying memory subsystems in various Apple products. Reasoning about memory subsystems is challenging due to its complex mechanism to allow concurrent executions of memory requests. Our team employs formalmethods tools to provide a mathematical guarantee that the systems are safe. Particularly, I have achieved verifying several memory components so we have better confidence in the safety of those components.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2016 -02/17/2021

Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2014 -06/03/2016

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

Seoul National University

03/01/2006 -02/26/2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Double major in Mathematical Sciences

- Graduated with honors (summa cum laude)

Publications

[1] Hemiola: A DSL and Verification Tools to Guide Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols. Joonwon Choi, Adam Chlipala, Arvind.

To appear in International Conference on Computer-Aided Verification (CAV'22). August 2022.

[2] Structural Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols. thesis

Joonwon Choi

Ph.D. Thesis in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. Massachusetts Institute of Technology.

Thesis Supervisor: Adam Chlipala and Arvind

[3] Integration Verification Across Software and Hardware for a Simple Embedded System. paper Andres Erbsen, Samuel Gruetter, Joonwon Choi, Clark Wood, Adam Chlipala.

Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'21).

[4] Kami: A Platform for High-Level Parametric Hardware Specification and its Modular Verification. paper Joonwon Choi, Muralidaran Vijayaraghavan, Benjamin Sherman, Adam Chlipala, Arvind. Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Functional Programming (ICFP'17). September 2017.

[5] EverCrypt: A Fast, Verified, Cross-Platform Cryptographic Provider. paper Jonathan Protzenko, Bryan Parno, Aymeric Fromherz, Chris Hawblitzel, Marina Polubelova, Karthikeyan Bhargavan, Benjamin Beurdouche, Joonwon Choi, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Natalia Kulatova, Tahina Ramananandro, Aseem Rastogi, Nikhil Swamy, Christoph M. Wintersteiger, and Santiago Zanella-Beguelin. IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP'20). May 2020.

[6] Crellvm: Verified Credible Compilation for LLVM. paper
Jeehoon Kang, Yoonseung Kim, Youngju Song, Juneyoung Lee, Sanghoon Park, Mark Dongyeon Shin, Yonghyun Kim, Sungkeun Cho, Joonwon Choi, Chung-Kil Hur, and Kwangkeun Yi.
Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'18).
June 2018.

[7] An Inlining Approach to Formal Hardware Semantics. <u>thesis</u> Joonwon Choi

M.S. Thesis in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Thesis Supervisor: Arvind

Honors & Awards

Software Engineering Intern (SWE Intern)

Kwanjeong Educational Fellowship MIT Emerson Scholarship for Private Music Study Top Honor (summa cum laude) Certification Seoul National University Presidential Science Scholarship Teaching Experience	Sep 2014 – May 2019 Sep 2014 – May 2018 Feb 2013 Mar 2006 – Feb 2013		
		MIT 6.887: Formal Reasoning About Programs Teaching Assistant	Spring 2017
		SNU 4190.310: Programming Languages Teaching Assistent	Fall 2013
		Working Experience	
		Apple, United States Formal Verification Engineer	03/15/2021 – Current
Microsoft Research Cambridge, United Kingdom Research Intern	07/02/2018 -09/21/2018		
allm Games, Korea Software Engineer (Skilled Industry Personnel as alternative military service)	04/13/2009 -09/12/2011		
Google, Korea	01/05/2009 -04/03/2009		

Last updated: May 18, 2022